Amalia Puri Handayani

Jakarta, February 2, 1985

H The 18th Residence Taman Rasuna, Kuningan Jakarta 12960

T+628161313350

E amalia@womenonweb.org amalia.handavani@amail.com

Profile

I have been working with people with many different backgrounds, cultures, ages, and levels. It gives me some experiences to communicate easily with people, even though I also enjoy being with myself only. I like being responsible, enjoy the challenge of new situations, and derive much pleasure from improving my abilities. I like to collaborate, contribute, and make a good team. I appreciate the concept of subjectivity, therefore I am keen on knowledge-sharing as well.

Experience

ASIAN DEVELOPMENT AND OUTREACH COORDINATOR, WOMEN ON WEB INTERNATIONAL FOUNDATION; JAKARTA - 2015—present

I am responsible to build network, do researches, and advocacy for Women on Web International Foundation activities in Asia. I also reply to worldwide emails regarding safe abortion help requests.

LECTURER, SEKOLAH TINGGI HUKUM INDONESIA JENTERA (INDONESIA JENTERA SCHOOL OF LAW); JAKARTA - 2016—present

I am responsible in making syllabus and teaching the subjects of Indonesian Languages, Laws in Society (particularly in public space issue and gender issue), and Academic Capacity.

CREATIVE MEDIA MANAGER, PUSAT STUDI HUKUM DAN KEBIJAKAN

(INDONESIAN CENTRE OF LAW AND POLICY STUDIES); JAKARTA - 2009-2017

I was responsible to "recreate" the researches and data for public use. I also lead the creative media division to manage internal knowledge for the organization. Beside that, I also proofread all publications. One of the creative media's product is LAWmotion; a way to spread the law issues in a different way, such as graphic recording.

RESEARCHER, PUSAT STUDI HUKUM DAN KEBIJAKAN

(INDONESIAN CENTRE OF LAW AND POLICY STUDIES); JAKARTA - 2010-2017

Beside doing the researches in relation to gender and public space, I often contributed in Legislative Drafting Training. As a facilitator, I involve in some publication as a writer, trainings as a facilitator, and drafting assisting.

Education

Erasmus University, International Institute of Social Studies, The Hague, The Netherlands, 2015
Master of Arts (MA) in Development Studies with an overall average grade of 79 (B)
(Research Paper: "Strategic Use of Public Space: Exploring Women, Labour, LGBT, and Anti-Corruption Actions in Bundaran HI, Jakarta")

University of Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia, 2010

Master of Science (M.Si.) in Women Studies with GPA 3,81 (of 4,00) (*cum laude*) (Thesis: "Gender-based Oppression in Indonesian Language: Semantics Studies with Feminism Perspective on Lemma in *Kamus Besar Bahasa Indonesia* (KBBI) 4th Edition 2008")

University of Indonesia, Depok, Indonesia, 2007

Bachelor of Humanities (S. Hum.) in Indonesian Studies with GPA 3,48 (of 4,00) (Thesis: "Lexical Variation in Indonesian Language Based on Gender")

Publishing

Problem Aturan Aborsi: Ancaman Kriminalisasi Korban Perkosaan, Ibu Hamil & Tenaga Kesehatan dalam RKUHP, Perkumpulan Keluarga Berencana Indonesia (PKBI), 2017.

"Kebutuhan atas Layanan Aborsi Telemedis di Indonesia dan Malaysia: Kajian pada Women on Web" dalam *Jurnal Perempuan: HKSR dan Kebijakan Pembangunan*, Vol. 93, Jurnal Perempuan, 2017.

UPR Briefing Paper Indonesia 2017, Joint Submission: Indonesian Civil Society Coalition for SRHR UPR, 2016.

Publik dan Reklame: Di Ruang Kota Jakarta, ruangrupa, 2013

Draftology, Pusat Studi Hukum dan Kebijakan, 2011

Merancang Peraturan untuk Perubahan, Pusat Studi Hukum dan Kebijakan, 2011

Pengetahuan dari Perempuan; Kumpulan Penelitian Tesis dan Wajah Lulusan Program Studi Kajian Wanita Program Pascasarjana Universitas Indonesia 1990-2010 (Buku Dua), Kajian Wanita UI, 2010.

Award

StuNed Scholarship Awardee, 2014 Completing Master Program with honor Cum Laude, University of Indonesia, 2010

Training, Seminar, Workshop, Conference: SRHR

- "Youth Advocacy Refresher Institute". Asian Safe Abortion Partnership (ASAP), Mumbai, India, 2019, as a speaker and participant
- "Need of Telemedical Abortion Service: Malaysia and Malaysia in 2015—2017", The 4th International Congress on Women's Health and Unsafe Abortion (IWAC 2019), Bangkok-Thailand, 2019, as a speaker.
- -"Layanan Aborsi Aman", Pelayanan Ramah Remaja, IHAP, Kupang, NTT, 2018, as a facilitator
- -Youth Advocacy Institute (Safe Abortion), Jakarta, 2018, as a facilitator
- "Telemedical Abortion Service", Women on Web, Kuala Lumpur, 2018, as a speaker
- -"Layanan Aborsi Aman untuk Pekerja Seks", Women on Web, Jakarta, 2018, as a speaker
- -The 2nd International Exhange Workshop, PINSAN, Manila, 2018, as a speaker
- -"Telemedical Abortion Service", Women on Web, Singapore, 2018, as a sepaker
- -Value Clarification and Attitude Transformation (VCAT) and Medical Abortion, Women on Web, Padang, 2018, as a facilitator
- -Value Clarification and Attitude Transformation (VCAT): Training of Trainers, IPAS, Jakarta, 2018, as a participant
- -The Power of Partnerships: Celebrating 10 years of movement building for Safe Abortion Advocacy, Bangkok, Thailand, February 2018, as a participant
- -The 9th Asia Pacific Conference on Reproductive and Sexual Health and Rights, 2017, Ha Long-Vietnam, as a poster presenter
- -Gender and Social Inclusion, Jakarta, 2017, as a trainer
- -Youth Advocacy Institution (Safe Abortion), Yogyakarta, 2017, as a participant
- -Universal Period Review Preparation on Safe Abortion Issue, 2016, as a participant
- -International Conference on Feminism, Jakarta, 2016, as a speaker
- -Training of Trainers: Gender and Social Inclusivity, West Java, 2016 as a participant
- -International Conference on Family Planning, Bali, 2016, as a participant